icarly.de 2019-06-30

# THE NICKELODEON GROUP PRIVACY POLICY AND YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS | Nick

## LAST UPDATED: 6/21/2017

(See [Summary of Most Significant Changes](http://legal.viacom.com/Changes/K+F) to learn more.)

Welcome! This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") describes our privacy practices for the "Nickelodeon Sites" of the "Nickelodeon Group." The Nickelodeon Group is a business unit of Viacom Media Networks, a division of Viacom International, Inc. The Nickelodeon Sites (or, individually, "Site") are the Internet websites, applications and other interactive services that are offered by the Nickelodeon Group for use on mobile devices, tablets, personal computers and any other devices that connect to the Internet. Some of the Nickelodeon Sites are intended for children and some are intended for older audiences. By accessing any of the Nickelodeon Sites, you are consenting to this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy describes what information the Nickelodeon Sites collect from users, including children, when they visit the Nickelodeon Sites; how such information is used and stored; when such information may be disclosed to third parties; how users, parents, and guardians can control the use and disclosure of collected information; and how information is protected.

Our visitors' privacy is important to us, and we recognize the need to provide additional privacy protection for children on the Nickelodeon Sites permitting such visitors. Our privacy practices are guided by the United States' Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998, as well as data privacy laws in the United States and other applicable countries. Younger visitors should always check with their parents or guardians before entering information on any website or mobile application and we encourage families to discuss their household guidelines regarding the online sharing of personal information. For a list of websites to which this Privacy Policy applies that are directed to children under 13 years of age, please click [here](http://www.nick.com/nick-assets/copy/nickelodeon-sites.html).

## SUMMARY

For your convenience, the following is a quick summary of our Privacy Policy. Please read the entire Privacy Policy for more detailed information.

WHAT INFORMATION WE COLLECT | 

In general, we collect three types of information:

  1. Information that you actively give to us (for example, during registration, sweepstakes, purchases or content submissions);
  2. Information we automatically collect about your computer or wireless devices (such as IP address, cookie ID, or other unique device identifiers); and
  3. Information we collect from third parties, including through third-party social media providers with whom you have registered.
  4. For more detailed information regarding the information we collect, please go here.

---|---  
HOW WE STORE SUCH INFORMATION. | 

We take reasonable precautions against the unauthorized access to or loss of your information, always with the goal of keeping our security up to date as cyber threats change. Despite such precautions, there is always a chance of unauthorized access to or loss of your information. If you think a third party has accessed your information, please contact us immediately as instructed below.

For more detailed information regarding how we store information, please go here.  
  
HOW WE USE SUCH INFORMATION. | 

In general, the information we collect may be used to respond to your requests; enable you to take advantage of Nickelodeon Sites features and services; personalize your experience and the advertising you see; send you special offers and promotions from Nickelodeon, the Viacom family of companies, and on behalf of third-parties whose products or services might be of interest to you; measure analytics; and manage and improve the services available on the Nickelodeon Sites. We may use your information in these ways when and where it is consistent with legal requirements to do so.

For more detailed information regarding how we use such information, please go here.  
  
INFORMATION WE SHARE WITH THIRD PARTIES. | 

Depending upon the circumstances, we may share collected information with (a) law enforcement or others as needed to protect or defend our rights and the rights of others; (b) third parties we hire to handle certain activities; (c) advertisers or third parties with whom we may partner to provide you additional content, products or services; (d) business partners who sponsor a sweepstakes or contest or who jointly offer a service or feature on the Nickelodeon Sites; (e) within the Viacom family of companies; (f) in the event of a corporate transaction; and (g) otherwise with your consent.

For more detailed information regarding our information sharing practices, please go here.  
  
WHAT INFORMATION OTHERS MAY COLLECT. | 

Third parties may collect and disclose certain identifiers, like IP address or cookie information, solely for the support of the internal operations of the Nickelodeon Sites, such as providing content or allowing features to run on the Nickelodeon Sites, serving contextual advertising, and using analytics and other tools to improve the quality and performance of the Nickelodeon Sites.

For more information about third party data collection, please go here.

Some of these third parties, such as advertising networks that serve targeted advertising on websites and online services intended for older audiences, or analytics service providers that analyze the performance of the Nickelodeon Sites may use their own unique identifiers, and their use of these technologies is within their control and not ours. These companies may use the information they collect from you consistent with their own privacy policies, which we encourage you to review.

For more information about these third parties and how you might be able to control how they use your information, please go here.  
  
YOUR CONTROL OVER YOUR INFORMATION. | 

You have the right to access, update and correct factual inaccuracies in any personally identifiable information we collect about you.

You can stop the delivery of commercial e-mail messages from the Nickelodeon Sites by following the instructions in e-mails you receive.

You may have choices about the use of your information by third parties wishing to deliver certain targeted advertising to you.

Parents and guardians can review any personally identifiable information collected about their children and request that such information be deleted and/or that no further information be collected.

For more detailed information regarding your control over your information, please go here and here.  
  
WHO WE ARE | 

The Nickelodeon Sites are made available by the Nickelodeon Group. If you have any questions about our information handling practices, including our practices with respect to children's personal information, please contact us at:

Nick.com CA Privacy Coordinator, c/o Nickelodeon Online, 1515 Broadway, New York, New York 10036. Or email us at: nickprivacy@nickonline.com. Or call this number: 212-846-2543.

Other corporate affiliates may collect or maintain information through the Nickelodeon Sites.

For more detailed information regarding who we are, please go here.  
  
## QUICK LINKS

### I.INFORMATION COLLECTION AND USE.

We may request or collect certain information when you visit the Nickelodeon Sites. However, visitors are required to share only the information that is reasonably necessary to participate in the particular activity.

A. Registration Information: The information required to register varies by Site, but may include: (a) birth date; (b) gender; (c) country; (d) state; (e) zip code; (f) user name and password; (g) wireless telephone number; (h) email address; and (i) other profile information such as avatar preferences, communications preferences, and interests. If the Site either is directed to children under 13 or has actual knowledge that a user is under 13 years old, the child may be asked to provide his or her parent's or guardian's email address. For certain countries, child visitors or their parents/guardians will receive an activation email and must follow the procedures or otherwise agree to the terms within the activation email within a certain time period to activate the account; accounts not activated within that time period will be deleted.

Registration information is used to enable visitors to log into their accounts across different devices and platforms; take advantage of site offerings; respond to visitor's requests for products, services, and information; send communications to users in connection with their account; manage games; serve appropriate material; customize the content you see when you visit the Nickelodeon Sites; and offer visitors special offers and promotions from Nickelodeon Sites and the "Viacom family of companies" (which comprises Viacom International Inc. and its subsidiaries and affiliates), as well as on behalf of selected third parties offering products, programs or services, that we believe may be of interest to you.

Certain non-child-directed Sites may offer visitors opportunities to apply for certain programs or other employment, training or internship opportunities. In order to submit an application for any one of these opportunities, the applicant may be required to supply other pertinent personal information including, without limitation, full name, postal address, telephone number(s) and email address. Additional personal information and other information may be requested during the application process (but may not be required). Such submissions are also subject to the policies regarding such respective programs. 

B. Social Platform Registrations and Social Media Plugins: Some of the Nickelodeon Sites permit or require users who are at least 13 years old to register or log into their account via a social networking platform such as Login with Facebook or Flux, or permit you to use social media plugins such as the Facebook "Like" or Google "+1" buttons. When you use these social networking platforms and plugins, your username and password for the services and other information available about you or collected from you on these services may be shared with us.

When you use social networking platforms and plugins, you share your information with them and their privacy policy applies to their collection, use, and disclosure of such information. In addition, they may be able to collect information about you, including your activity on the Nickelodeon Sites, and they may notify your connections on the social networking platform about your use of the Nickelodeon Sites. Such services may also employ unique identifiers which allow your activity to be monitored across multiple websites for purposes of delivering more targeted advertising to you. For more information about logging into Facebook, please go [here](https://www.facebook.com/help/292105707596942/). Please note that their privacy policies may be different from our own and we encourage you to read them. 

C. Computer Information Collected by Us: When visitors come to a Site, we may automatically collect certain information from their computers or mobile devices, such as the type of computer operating system (e.g., Windows XP or Mac OS), the visitor's IP address, the web browser (e.g., Internet Explorer, Safari, Chrome and Firefox), UDID (for certain mobile devices), information about the websites visited before and after visiting the Site, the web pages and advertisements viewed and links clicked on within the Nickelodeon Sites, interactions with e-mail messages sent by a Site or the Viacom family of companies ( _e.g._ , links clicked on and whether the messages were opened or forwarded), information collected through the use of unique identifiers such as cookies (see below), information regarding the Internet service provider, and other standard server log information ("Computer Information").

This Privacy Policy does not, unless specifically stated, apply to any personal information or other information collected by any other company or collected in any other manner or by any other website, application or other interactive service offered by the Viacom family of companies.  Such information collection may be governed by separate privacy policies or notices.  In particular, [please see our Privacy Shield Privacy Policy for](http://www.viacom.com/privacypolicy/Documents/Privacy_Shield_Privacy_Policy_Viacom.pdf) information on our privacy policy and practices with respect to personal information transferred to the U.S.

We may use cookies, web beacons, tokens or similar technologies (collectively referred to as "Tracking Technologies") on the Nickelodeon Sites. "Cookies" (which may be html files, Flash files or other technology) are text files that help store user preferences and activity. "Web beacons" (also known as image tags, gif or web bugs) are small pieces of code used to collect advertising data, such as counting page views, promotion views or advertising responses. "Tokens" are unique persistent identifiers that are generated and sent from a server, such as Adobe's Pass service, to a user's device to identify an interaction session, such as the authentication for a user's cable provider service, and which are usually stored as an HTTP cookie. The Site and/or third parties may use Tracking Technologies to collect Computer Information automatically as you browse the Site and the web.

We may use Tracking Technologies to help tailor our content, allow users to move between certain Nickelodeon Sites without logging into each Site, enable the internal functioning of the Nickelodeon Sites, understand Site and internet usage, improve or customize the content, offerings or advertisements on this Site, personalize your experience on the Site (for example, to recognize you by name when you return to the Site), understand your interactions with email messages originating from the Nickelodeon Sites or the Viacom family of companies (such as the links clicked on and whether the messages were opened or forwarded), save your password, save your online game or video player settings, enable you to use shopping carts, help us offer you products, programs or services that may be of interest to you, deliver relevant advertising, maintain and administer the Nickelodeon Sites. These Tracking Technologies collect "click stream" data and additional other information regarding your visits to the Nickelodeon Sites (such as your visits to specific webpages, use of features, purchasing history or preferences), may collect such other information across multiple sessions on the Nickelodeon Sites and other websites offered by the Viacom family of companies and may also collect your IP address or some other identifier unique to the device you use to access the site ("Identifier"). An Identifier may be automatically assigned to any device you use to access the Nickelodeon Sites. When a cable television service subscriber authenticates his cable television service to view full episodes of Nickelodeon programing in the Nick mobile app, a third party token is stored on the user's mobile device so that the subscriber can view Nickelodeon television episodes in the future without having to re-authenticate his cable service subscription.

By visiting a Site, whether as a registered user or otherwise, you acknowledge, understand and hereby agree that you are giving us your consent to set and access Cookies on your device and track your activities and your use of a Site through these Tracking Technologies and Identifiers and that we may use Tracking Technologies in the emails we send to you.

The Nickelodeon Sites adhere to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising. Click here for more information about the Nickelodeon Sites and online behavioral advertising. Nickelodeon does not behaviorally target advertising to children under 13 on sites that are directed to children or where Nickelodeon has actual knowledge that a user is under 13.

Our Third Party Advertising Service Providers (as defined in Section D) do not have access to Tracking Technologies set by the Nickelodeon Sites except to the extent necessary to provide services to the Site. The Third Party Advertising Service Providers, as well as advertisers, may themselves set and access their own Tracking Technologies on your Device if you choose to have Tracking Technologies enabled in your browser (or, for Flash cookies, if you have not removed them) and/or they may otherwise have access to other information about you.

You have a number of options with respect to the Tracking Technologies set by the Nickelodeon Sites:

  * You can prevent the use of certain Tracking Technologies (other than Flash cookies) by using the controls in your Web browser. To do so, you must complete both of the steps following your browser type below:

  *     * Internet Explorer
    *       1. _Delete existing Tracking Technologies_ through the "Internet Options" sub-option of the "Tools" menu option of your browser or otherwise as directed by your browser's support feature; and

      2. _Disable future Tracking Technologies_ by using the same browser controls. Additional information on disabling most Tracking Technologies may be available through your browser's support feature. (See the "help" section of your browser for more information.)

  *     * Google Chrome
    *       1. _Delete existing Tracking Technologies_ through the "Clear Browsing Data..." sub-option of the "Tools" menu option of your browser or otherwise as directed by your browser's support feature; and

      2. _Disable future Tracking Technologies_ by using the same browser controls. Additional information on disabling most Tracking Technologies may be available through your browser's support feature. (See the "help" section of your browser for more information.)

  *     * Mozilla Firefox
    *       1. _Delete existing Tracking Technologies_ through the "Clear Recent History..." sub-option of the "History" menu option of your browser or otherwise as directed by your browser's support feature; and

      2. _Disable future Tracking Technologies_ by using the same browser controls. Additional information on disabling most Tracking Technologies may be available through your browser's support feature. (See the "help" section of your browser for more information.)

  * You may be able to have the device you use to access the Nickelodeon Sites warn you each time a cookie or most other Tracking Technologies is being set (other than Flash cookies), or you can choose to turn off such warnings. This is done through your browser on the device you use to access the Nickelodeon Sites. Additional information on warnings and removal of warnings may be available through your browser's support feature.

Please note that deleting, rejecting, disabling or turning off Tracking Technologies through the above options will not remove Flash cookies. For more information about Flash cookies and how to remove them from your computer, please click [here](http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html).

Please be aware that certain areas and features of Nickelodeon Sites can only be accessed in conjunction with Tracking Technologies, and that disabling Tracking Technologies might prevent you from accessing such content.

D. Computer Information Collected By Others: Third parties may collect, use or disclose cookie information, IP addresses or other identifiers from devices and/or browsers of users who visit Nickelodeon Sites for the purposes of supporting the internal operations of the Nickelodeon Sites, which can include, for example: 1) providing content or allowing features to run on the Sites; 2) serving contextual advertising; and 3) using analytics and other tools to improve the quality and performance of the Nickelodeon Sites. To the extent that third parties collect any personal information for any other purposes about users of the Nickelodeon Sites that are directed to children under 13 years of age, or where Nickelodeon has actual knowledge that a user is under 13 years of age, we will notify parents or guardians, including by listing those third parties here [<http://www.nick.com/nick-assets/copy/third-parties.html>], and will request parental consent for the collection of that data.

Among the service providers we engage, Nickelodeon Sites use a variety of third-party advertising networks, data exchanges, traffic measurement service providers, marketing analytics service providers, and other third-party service providers (collectively, "Third Party Advertising Service Providers") to, for example, serve advertisements on the Nickelodeon Sites, help prevent you from seeing repeated advertisements, and measure and analyze traffic on the Nickelodeon Sites. On websites directed to older audiences, Third Party Advertising Service Providers may also be used to facilitate targeting of advertisements and measure and analyze advertising effectiveness ("Targeting Services"). These Targeting Services enable us, for older audiences, to display advertisements based on your visits to the Nickelodeon Sites and other websites you have visited and may include delivering advertisements or other content for products and services that may interest you. Targeting Services also enable us to research the usefulness of certain advertisements. See here for more information on this Site's use of Nielsen's proprietary measurement software to collect and use video viewing metrics and other information. Nickelodeon does not behaviorally target advertising to children under 13 on sites that are directed to children or where Nickelodeon has actual knowledge that a user is under 13. 

These Third Party Advertising Service Providers do not have access to Tracking Technologies set by the Nickelodeon Sites except to the extent necessary to provide services to the Nickelodeon Sites. The Third Party Advertising Service Providers, as well as advertisers, may themselves set and access their own Tracking Technologies on your device if you choose to have Tracking Technologies enabled in your browser (or, for Flash cookies, if you have not removed them) and/or they may otherwise have access to other information about you. In addition, Third Party Advertising Service Providers may collect aggregate log data separately and independently from what the Nickelodeon Sites collect.

You should be aware that different rules might apply to the collection, use or disclosure of your information by third parties in connection with their advertisements, promotions and other websites you encounter on the Internet. The use of such technology by these third parties is within their control and not the Nickelodeon Sites. Even if we have a relationship with the third party, we do not control those sites or their policies and practices regarding your information and those sites may use the information they collect from you consistent with their own privacy policies, which we encourage you to review. We encourage you to research and direct any of your questions in this regard to these third parties.

With respect to the Tracking Technologies set by Third Party Advertising Service Providers and advertisers (and outside the control of the Nickelodeon Sites), you have a number of options:

  * You can opt-out of the use of information for these advertising purposes by two such Third Party Advertising Service Providers, Adobe and DoubleClick by using those Providers' opt-out tools. You can access Adobe's tool at <http://www.donottarget.com/> and DoubleClick's at <http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/technologies/ads/>. We also may from time to time permit other Third Party Advertising Service Providers and Advertisers to collect Information on the Nickelodeon Sites. Some of these Providers and Advertisers may participate in the Network [Advertising Initiative's Opt-Out Tool](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp) and/or the [Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/) Please click on the links to these tools to learn more about your choices.

  * **_Nielsen Measurement:_** The player on this website may feature Nielsen's proprietary measurement software which will collect and use certain video viewing metrics and other information, in accordance with Nielsen's digital measurement privacy policy. For more information about Nielsen's measurement software, see <http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy> and see the "Choices" section of that digital measurement privacy policy to learn about your choices with respect to Nielsen's measurement, including your opt-out options if you do not wish to participate in such measurement and the scope of any opt-out options. 

  * Please note the following with respect to opting out of Tracking Technologies set by Third Party Advertising Service Providers and advertisers:

  * _The opt-out tools discussed above are "cookie based_." This means that the tools rely on cookies to remember your choices with respect to the use of your information by the parties that offer you those choices. If you opt-out but then use the controls in your browser to delete all Tracking Technologies, you may have to opt-out again, a second time, in order to re-establish your opt-out preferences.

  * _Opt-outs are browser-specific_. This means, for example, that if you opt out while using Internet Explorer 9, this choice will not affect the collection of information collected by Tracking Technologies when you use Mozilla Firefox on the same device. It also means that opting out on one device will not affect the collection of information by Tracking Technologies on other devices you may use to access the Nickelodeon Sites.

  * You also can prevent the use of certain Tracking Technologies (other than Flash cookies) on a particular device by using the controls in your Web browser. To do so, you must complete both of the following steps:

  1. Delete existing Tracking Technologies through the "Internet Options" sub-option of the "Tools" menu option of your browser or otherwise as directed by your browser's support feature; and

  2. Disable future Tracking Technologies by using the same browser controls. Additional information on disabling most Tracking Technologies may be available through your browser's support feature. (See the "help" section of your browser for more information.)

  * You may be able to set the device you use to access the Nickelodeon Sites to warn you each time a cookie or most other Tracking Technologies is being set (other than Flash cookies), or you can choose to turn off such warnings. This is done through your browser on the device you use to access the Nickelodeon Sites. Additional information on warnings and removal of warnings may be available through your browser's support feature.

  * Opting-out of, deleting, rejecting, disabling or turning off Third Party Advertising Service Providers' Tracking Technologies does not mean that you will no longer receive online ads. Opting-out of, deleting, rejecting, disabling or turning off Third Party Advertising Service Providers' Tracking Technologies only means that such ads will no longer be tailored to your specific viewing habits or interests, but you will continue to see ads on the Nickelodeon Sites.

  * PLEASE NOTE THAT THE USE AND STORAGE OF FLASH COOKIES TYPICALLY CANNOT BE CONTROLLED THROUGH YOUR BROWSER. For more information about Flash cookies and how to remove them from your computer, please click [here](http://kb2.adobe.com/cps/526/52697ee8.html).

Do-Not-Track Signals and Similar Mechanisms. Some web browsers may transmit "do-not-track" signals to the websites with which the browser communicates. Because of differences in how web browsers incorporate and activate this feature, it is not always clear whether users intend for these signals to be transmitted, or whether they even are aware of them. There currently is disagreement, including among participants in the leading Internet standards-setting organization, concerning what, if anything, websites should do when they receive such signals.

We currently do not take action in response to these signals, but, if and when a final standard is established and accepted, we may reassess how to respond to these signals. Instead, as set forth above, please see the link to the Self-Regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising program that we follow that offers you choice regarding Information collected for online behavioral advertising purposes and the browser cookie controls and other mechanisms described above in Section I(C).

E. Contests, Sweepstakes and Promotions: The Nickelodeon Sites may offer online contests, sweepstakes and promotions. To enter these contests, sweepstakes and promotions, you may be required to provide your first name and email address and/or additional information required for the management of the contest, sweepstakes or promotion. On sites that either are directed to children under 13 or where we have actual knowledge that a user is a child under 13, we may collect the child's e-mail address to enter the child in the contest, sweepstakes or promotion, store such child's email address for the duration of the contest, sweepstakes or promotion, and use it for notification if he or she is the winner. For certain contests, sweepstakes or promotions on such sites, we may ask for the email address of the child's parent or guardian to inform the parent or guardian of his or her child's entry and give the parent or guardian the option to have the child's entry deleted.

F. Electronic Postcards and Messages: Some Nickelodeon Sites provide visitors the opportunity to send electronic postcards and "wish lists" of items they want to family or friends, which means we will send, on the visitor's behalf, email messages to family and/or friends. To do so, visitors must provide the email address of the recipient of such electronic postcards or email messages. Visitors must only provide email addresses of people who they know would be happy to receive such electronic postcards or email messages. Email addresses provided to us for this purpose are used solely to send the requested postcard or email message and are deleted from our system once the postcard or message is sent. In some cases, we may offer visitors an incentive ( _e.g._ , points to be used in an online game) for referring information about products to the visitor's family or friends. In such cases, we will comply with all applicable legal requirements. Please note that this feature may not be available to visitors in certain regions or countries.

G. Electronic Newsletters: Visitors can provide their email addresses to receive email newsletters and promotions from the Nickelodeon Group, the Viacom family of companies, and our business partners. Visitors may change their preferences regarding emails at any time through the unsubscribe link in the newsletters or, for certain Nickelodeon Sites, by logging into and changing the preferences for their account.

When visitors to Nickelodeon Sites that are directed to children under 13 ask to receive our email newsletter(s), they will be asked to provide their first name, email address and the email address of their parent/guardian. We will send the child's parent/guardian a notification email informing them of the child's request to receive by email the newsletter on an ongoing basis and give the parent/guardian the option to have his or her child's information removed from our newsletter database. The link to remove the child's information will expire approximately 48 hours from the time it is sent, but at any time after receiving this notification email, the child's parent/guardian may request that we stop sending the child the newsletter(s) by following the "unsubscribe" instructions found at the end of any of the newsletter emails. Parents/guardians may at any time review any personally identifiable information collected online about their child. See section V(B) below. When a child provides a parent's/guardian's email address when signing up for newsletter(s), that email address is used to send the notification email message and is subsequently deleted from our system. 

H. Interactive Features and Services: Some of the Nickelodeon Sites offer interactive features and services, such as message boards and comment boxes. For certain countries, on Nickelodeon Sites that either are directed to children under 13 or when we have actual knowledge that a user is a child under 13 years old, we either will obtain the consent of the child's parent/guardian before allowing the child to use these interactive features and services or use reasonable technical measures to delete all or virtually all personal information from a child's postings before they are made public and delete such information from our records. We use the information collected through interactive features and services to enable you to participate in such features and services. 

I. Text Messaging Marketing and Promotions: Consistent with local law, appropriately aged visitors may have the opportunity to register for special promotions, services, news, programming and information delivered via text messaging ("Text Services"). If we do so, we will require your prior express consent for any Text Services in accordance with the nature of the Text Service and applicable laws, rules and regulations.

When you register for Text Services, you acknowledge, understand and agree that you may be charged by your wireless carrier for the ability to send or receive all such messages. The standard messaging rates of your wireless carrier shall apply to all Text Services, unless noted otherwise. Under no circumstances will the Nickelodeon Group or the Viacom family of companies be responsible for any wireless email or text messaging charges incurred by such visitor or by a person that has access to a visitor's wireless device, telephone number, or email address. If you change or deactivate your wireless telephone number, you agree to notify us when your wireless telephone number is no longer associated with you and identify such wireless phone number to ensure that future messages directed to you are not sent to the person to whom your old number has been or will be assigned. We may share your personal information with the operational service providers that assist us in delivering Text Services and similar services to you, with the Viacom family of companies and as otherwise provided in "Disclosure to Third Parties" below.

Please note that you may always send a text message that says "HELP" to receive help on text messaging.

J. Geolocation Information: We may collect and store information about your geographic location, but we will only collect precise geolocation information sufficient to identify street name and name of a city or town on Nickelodeon Sites that either are directed to users over 13 or when we have actual knowledge that a user is over 13 years old and only if you enable your computer or mobile device to send us location information. You may be able to change the settings on your computer or mobile device to prevent it from providing us with such information. We use this information, for example, to enable visitors to take advantage of Site offerings; respond to visitor's requests for products, services, and information; manage games; customize the content visitors see when visiting the Nickelodeon Sites; and to offer visitors special offers and promotions from Nickelodeon Sites and the Viacom family of companies, as well as on behalf of selected third parties offering products, programs or services that we believe may be of interest to our visitors. By accepting this Privacy Policy and using the applicable Site, you hereby consent to the collection and storage of such geolocation information as described above.

K. Financial Information: We collect and use financial information, such as credit card numbers and security codes, for the limited purposes described below.

i. _Arcades_ : Users who are of legal age to form a binding contract may purchase games available on the Nickelodeon Sites ( _e.g._ , games from Shockwave.com). Purchasing such games may require providing information to process the order including full name, billing and/or shipping addresses, billing address, email address, credit card number, control payment number, PIN, card security code, expiration date and/or a phone number. After successfully entering a valid credit card number/expiration date and completing the order process, an account is created. We use this information to process the order and to send order confirmations via email, as well as to send information about products and services of interest and as otherwise required by law. If you make purchases using a pre-paid card, we will not require you to enter any personally identifiable information to complete your purchase.

ii. _Consumer Products_ : Certain of the Nickelodeon Sites provide pages and/or links to pages offering visitors who are of legal age to form a binding contract the opportunity to purchase consumer products (the "Shops"). To do so, visitors need to provide contact, shipping, billing and credit information. These pages may be hosted and operated by a third party that is independent and separate from the Nickelodeon Sites. This third party collects personal information about shop visitors and may share this information with us. We use this information to process the order and to send order confirmations via email, as well as to send information about products and services of interest and as otherwise required by law. Before providing information on these pages, we encourage you to review the posted privacy policies which govern such third party's use of your information, as they may differ from ours.

iii. _Virtual Items/Memberships_ : Some of the Nickelodeon Sites may offer memberships, online subscriptions and/or virtual items for use in conjunction with the Nickelodeon Sites' games. When you enter into a transaction for a membership, subscription, virtual item or similar transaction, you may be asked to provide the credit card and/or billing information and email address. We will use this information to fulfill your specified requests, as well as to inform you about additional products or service opportunities and as otherwise required by law. Please also see the information regarding payment processors in Section II(B) below.

L. Other Data Collection and Use.

We collect search query information when visitors search for information on the Nickelodeon Sites. We also collect information from visitors when they contact us with questions and comments.

We may use this information, along with any of the other information described above, to (i) analyze use of the Nickelodeon Sites and understand and improve our service offerings; (ii) prevent potentially prohibited or illegal activities; and (iii) for any other purposes disclosed to you at the time we collect your information or pursuant to your consent.

We may combine information collected through the Nickelodeon Sites with information we collect from other sources ( _e.g._ , social media integration services), other Viacom family of company's sites, offline records or publicly available information). It is your responsibility to provide complete and accurate information and to keep such information up to date. We are not responsible for any problem or liability arising from your failure to do so.

### II. DISCLOSURE TO THIRD PARTIES.

We may share your information with third parties for the limited purposes described below. In the U.S., parents of children under the age of 13 have the option of consenting to the collection and use of their child's personal information without consenting to the disclosure of that information to certain third parties.

A. Law Enforcement and Safety.

You acknowledge, consent, and agree to the extent legally permissible in your jurisdiction to allow us to access, preserve, and/or disclose the information we collect and/or content you provide to us (including information you may have posted on bulletin boards or internal site communication systems) to a law enforcement agency or other third parties if required to do so by law or with a good faith belief that such access, preservation, or disclosure is reasonably necessary to: (a) comply with legal process; (b) enforce the Terms of Use of the respective Nickelodeon Sites; (c) respond to claims that the content violates the rights of third parties; (d) respond to your requests for customer service; or (e) protect the rights, property, or personal safety of the owners of the Nickelodeon Sites, any user of the Nickelodeon Sites, a third party or the general public. We also may disclose user information whenever we believe disclosure is necessary to limit our legal liability; to protect or defend our rights or property; or protect the safety, rights, or property of others.

If you have concerns about the conduct of a particular user, please send an e-mail to [nickprivacy@nickonline.com](mailto:nickprivacy@nickonline.com). This email is not to contact us about the status of your account.

B. Agents.

Information collected through the Nickelodeon Sites may be transferred, disclosed or shared with third parties engaged by us to handle and deliver certain activities, such as message boards, sweepstakes and contests, e-cards, payment processing, newsletters, and advisory boards, and to perform other technical and processing functions, such as sending postal mail and email, maintaining data integrity, programming operations, user services or technology services. We may provide these third parties information collected as needed to perform their functions, but they are prohibited from using it for other purposes and specifically agree to maintain the confidentiality of such information. Some of these agents, such as payment processors, may request additional information during the course of offering their services. Before you provide additional information to third party agents, we encourage visitors to review their privacy policies and information collection practices.

C. Third Parties/Advertisers.

Some Nickelodeon Sites partner with outside third parties to provide you with additional content, products, or services that we believe may be of interest. For example, we may partner with a greeting card company, software manufacturer, social media plugin provider, mobile phone provider or cable television service provider to offer you electronic cards, games, social networking, text messaging services or customized video content. These partners operate websites and services that are separate and independent from the Nickelodeon Sites and, accordingly, may have their own privacy policies. If you consent or register with one of our partners, that means you grant the Nickelodeon Sites permission to give your registration and other information, including e-mail address, to that third party. If you have identified yourself as residing in the EU, we will not share your email address or other personally identifiable information with third parties for advertising purposes unless you have "opted-in."

In addition, Third Party Advertising Service Providers may use their own Tracking Technologies to gather information about you. Please see Section I(D) above for more detailed information regarding such use of Tracking Technologies.

For more information on our use of third party advertisers and the self-regulatory principles, please click [here](http://srp.mtvn.com/sitefaq.html).

D. Co-Branded Sites and Features

Some Nickelodeon Sites offer co-branded services and features, such as events and promotions that we put together with another company ("Co-Branded Partner"). Such services may be hosted on a Site and/or our Co-Branded Partner's website. We may share your information with our Co-Branded Partner and your voluntary use of or participation in a co-branded service or feature means that you opt-in and affirmatively consent to both the Nickelodeon Sites and our Co-Branded Partner collecting and using the information you provided during registration and/or in connection with the specific co-branded feature for fulfillment, marketing or administrative purposes. If you wish to opt-out of a Co-Branded Partner's future use of your information for marketing purposes, you will need to contact the Co-Branded Partner directly. The Co-Branded Partner will be identified on the co-branded feature or service.

E. Viacom and Other Affiliated Businesses

The Nickelodeon Sites are part of the Viacom family of companies. Where permitted by law, we may share information we collect about you within the websites of the Viacom family of companies' and other affiliated businesses so that we can, for example, provide you with information about products and services that might interest you.

F. Business Transfer

In the event that assets relating to one or more of the Nickelodeon Sites are transferred or sold to another entity as a result of, for example, a corporate sale, merger, consolidation, asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy, information collected at the Nickelodeon Sites may be transferred to the acquiring company.

G. With Your Consent

We may otherwise disclose your information pursuant to your consent.

### III. U.S. GOVERNING LAW.

The Nickelodeon Sites are designed for and targeted to U.S. audiences and are governed by and operated in accordance with the laws of the U.S. While users from countries other than the U.S. may access certain of the Nickelodeon Sites, we make no representation that the Nickelodeon Sites are operated in accordance with the laws or regulations of, or governed by, other nations.

If you are located outside of the U.S., you use this Site at your own risk and initiative and you, not us, are responsible for compliance with any applicable local and national laws. Please be aware that any personal information and other information you provide to us or we obtain as a result of your use of this Site shall be collected in the U.S. and/or transferred to the U.S. and subject to U.S. law.

By using this Site, participating in any Site activities and/or providing us with your personal information and other information, you (a) consent to the transfer and/or processing of any Information to and in the U.S., (b) acknowledge that U.S. law may provide a lower standard of protection for personal data than the laws of your location and (c) understand that we shall collect, transfer, store, process and/or deal with your Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and U.S. law. Consequently, to the full extent permitted by law, you hereby waive any claims relating to the processing of your personal information or other information in accordance with this Privacy Policy that may arise under the laws and regulations that apply to you in or of any other country or jurisdiction.

### IV. SECURITY, STORAGE AND RETENTION OF INFORMATION.

The Nickelodeon Sites maintain reasonable technical and organizational steps to help ensure that information collected is secure, including limiting the number of people who have physical access to our database servers and use of electronic security systems and password protections which guard against unauthorized access. The Nickelodeon Sites conduct financial transactions via secured transmissions. We limit access to visitor's information to employees and contractors who are authorized for the proper handling of such information, and any employee found violating our standards of security and confidentiality will be subject to our disciplinary processes. We also take reasonable steps to help make sure our third-party agents protect the security of your personal information. However, as with most Internet sites or services, it is possible that third parties may unlawfully access such personal information through a number of means despite our efforts.

Information collected at the Nickelodeon Sites will not be stored for longer than is necessary for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy, or to otherwise meet legal requirements.

### V. ACCESSING AND CORRECTING INFORMATION.

A. Reviewing Your Information

You have the right to access, update and correct factual inaccuracies in personally identifiable information that we collect online at the Nickelodeon Sites, subject to certain exceptions. To do so, you should log into your account or you may e-mail us at [nickprivacy@nickonline.com](mailto:nickprivacy@nickonline.com). To help protect your privacy and the security of your personally identifiable information, we will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access.

See the Terms of Use for how registered users of this Site who are California residents and are under 18 years of age may request removal of content or information in postings.

B. Parental Access

Parents/guardians of children under the age of 13 can print out and mail or fax us a signed form that allows them to review any personally identifiable information collected about their child, have this information deleted, and/or request that there be no further collection or use of their child's personally identifiable information. You can download the form [here](http://www.nick.com/info/personal-information-access.html). We will take steps to verify the identity of anyone requesting personally identifiable information about a child and to ensure that the person is in fact the child's parent or legal guardian.

###  VI. ONLINE SAFETY.

Some of the Nickelodeon Sites offer you and your child an online safety guide which we encourage you to use as starting point for discussing safety and privacy concerns with your child. Of course, involvement in your family's online lives is the most important safety tool available. Some of the various guides are available here:

###  VII. LINKS TO THIRD PARTIES.

The websites that comprise the Nickelodeon Sites may contain links to other sites, including those of sponsors, advertisers, social networking platforms, and survey companies. These other websites are governed by their own privacy policies or information collection practices, which may be substantially different from ours. We encourage visitors to other websites to review the privacy policies and information collection practices of those websites.

###  VIII. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS.

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits our visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of personal information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email to or write us: [nickprivacy@nickonline.com](mailto:nickprivacy@nickonline.com) email, or you may contact us via regular mail at:

Nick.com CA Privacy Coordinator

Nickelodeon Online

1515 Broadway

New York, New York 10036

This document is the sole statement of the Nickelodeon Sites' Privacy Policy and no summary, restatement or other version thereof, or other privacy statement or policy, in any form, including, without limitation, machine-generated, is valid. In interpreting this Agreement, the English version governs the interpretation and meaning of the obligation set forth herein. To the extent there is an ambiguity or conflict with the Privacy Policy in other languages, the Privacy Policy in English governs.

### IX. CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND NOTICE.

We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Policy at any time for any reason in our sole discretion by posting an updated Privacy Policy without advance notice to you. Such revisions shall be effective immediately upon posting and if you use the Site after they become effective it will signify your agreement to be bound by the changes. We shall post or display notices of material changes on the Site's homepage or otherwise on the Site and/or e-mail you or notify you upon login about these changes; the form of such notice is at our discretion. However, we encourage you to check this Privacy Policy often for updates.

### X. CONTACT US

If you have any other questions about our information handling practices, including our practices with respect to children's personal information, or would like further information regarding the Nickelodeon Sites that are directed to children under 13 years of age, please contact us at:

Nick.com CA Privacy Coordinator

c/o Nickelodeon Online

1515 Broadway

New York, New York 10036

Or email us at:  

Or call this number:  
212-846-2543

Other corporate affiliates may collect or maintain information through the Nickelodeon Sites.
